<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AMT Simplified</title>
    <link>https://amtsimplified.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AMT Simplified</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amtsimplified.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the AMT</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/amt-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/amt-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021)
 The Alternative Minimum Tax (AMT) is a separate tax that you have to calculate in parallel to your regular income tax. Each has a slightly different set of rules for what is deductible and different limits to the marginal tax brackets.
Every year you, or your tax filing program, actually calculates both your regular income tax and alternative minimum tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences between AMT and Regular Income Tax</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/amt-regular-tax-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/amt-regular-tax-differences/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021)
In addition, this article only highlights some of the most commonly used parts of the tax code. If you are in a unique situation, always consult with a tax accountant for any detailed questions
 Before diving into how the AMT is actually calculated, it may be helpful to visually see the differences between the ordinary income tax that you may be familiar with and the alternative minimum tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Calculate the Alternative Minimum Tax</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/amt-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/amt-taxes/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021)
In addition, this article only highlights some of the most commonly used parts of the tax code. If you are in a unique situation, always consult with a tax accountant for any detailed questions
 How to calculate the AMT How the Alternative Minimum Tax is determined can be broken up into a few broad steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Student Loan Interest Deduction?</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/what-is-sli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/what-is-sli/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021)
 Quick Summary  You can deduct up to $2,500 when filing taxes if you paid interest to a qualified student loan, alongside other criteria You cannot use the deduction if you are filing as: married, filing separately, make over certain income thresholds, or are claimed as a dependent on someone else&amp;rsquo;s tax return The $2,500 amount you can deduct also gradually decreases if you hit a certain phase-out MAGI threshold  Do I Qualify?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Mortgage Interest Deduction?</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/what-is-mortgage-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/what-is-mortgage-interest/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021)
 Quick Summary  If you own a home and paid your monthly mortgage bill, you can deduct the portion of those payments that went towards paying down the interest on your loan Because of the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act of 2017, you may not be able to deduct all of the interest. You can only deduct the interest paid on the portion of your principal up to $750,000  What is the Mortgage Interest Deduction?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the SALT Deduction?</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/what-is-salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/what-is-salt/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021)
 Quick Summary  The State and Local Tax (SALT) deduction is primarily made up of your property tax, but also includes either state income tax or state/local sales tax The deduction was lowered to a maximum of $10,000 due to the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act of 2017, severely limiting the amount you can deduct If you take the SALT deduction you also choose to itemize your deduction as opposed to taking the standard deduction The SALT deduction is not an eligible deduction for AMT purposes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Medical Expense Deduction?</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/what-is-medical-expense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/posts/what-is-medical-expense/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021)
 Quick Summary  You can deduct medical and dental expenses that in total exceed 10% of your AGI when filing for your taxes There are a variety of things you can deduct you may not have considered, including travel costs or certain premiums Using this deduction means you would be taking the itemized deduction as opposed to the regular standard deduction The Medical expense deduction is not an eligible deduction for AMT purposes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMT Calculator</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/amt-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/amt-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021), and only applies to Federal Taxes
This calculator only highlights some of the most commonly used parts of the tax code. If you are in a unique situation, always consult with a tax accountant for any detailed questions
Coming Soon: AMT calculators for non-ISOs, Additional Filing Statuses, Dependents Credits, and of course, a better design for this calculator (Minimum Viable Product!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incentive Stock Option Tax Planner</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/iso-exercise-planner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/iso-exercise-planner/</guid>
      <description>Please note details in this article are relevant for the 2020 tax year (filing in 2021), and only applies to Federal Taxes
This calculator only highlights some of the most commonly used parts of the tax code. If you are in a unique situation, always consult with a tax accountant for any detailed questions
Coming Soon: Allowing for inputs of if you sell exercised stock in the same calendar year, aesthetics, and having your inputs save over from this planner to the AMT calculator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is &#39;AMT Simplified&#39;</title>
      <link>https://amtsimplified.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amtsimplified.com/about/</guid>
      <description>AMT Simplified is a site dedicated to helping you understand, calculate, and plan for your Alternative Minimum Tax. It&amp;rsquo;s my hope this website can help save you money!
Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Dion. The way I found out about AMT was likely the same way you found out about it - being told I owe money to the government after filing my taxes one beautiful day in April. After multiple google searches and even sifting through IRS documentation, I realized it was incredibly difficult to find information on:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>